Tobalase A. Akinyemi

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Plot 1, Block D, Babatunde Estate, Off Ikirun Road, Osogbo.

□ +234 810 551 2758 | ■ tobalase.akinyemi@noth.i.ng | 回 funspectre | ♦ funspectre | □ tobalase-akinyemi

Summary_

Has interacted with computers since 2006 and coded them since 2009. Proficient with a range of programming languages and equivalent web frameworks. Looking to write software of social and professional relevance while solving adequately challenging problems. Writes and deploys high quality code in an efficient fashion using DevOps tools and practices.

Skills ____

DevOps Docker, Dokku, Gitlab, Shell

Back-end Laravel, Express, Rails, REST API

Front-end Vue, Vuex, React, Redux

Databases PostgreSQL, MariaDB, MongoDB

Programming Languages Javascript (Node.js), PHP, Ruby, Go, HTML, CSS, SASS

Work Experience _____

IndieTech Solutions

Abuja, Nigeria

Web Developer Jul. 2019 - Nov. 2019

- Implemented REST APIs for a food delivery service using Node.js, Express & MongoDB.
- Created client-side bindings to the REST API in a Vue.js web application.
- · Assisted in setting up a CI/CD pipeline for both server-side and client-side components reducing deployment times significantly.
- Ensured code formatting and style consistency using linters, formatters and git hooks.

Boughview Innovations Lagos, Nigeria

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jan. 2017 - Apr. 2019

- Provisioned virtual private servers with TLS support for all projects automating the process using shell scripts.
- Built fully automated continuous deployment pipelines using tools like Gitlab CI and Dokku to establish an Heroku like deployment environment.
- Designed and implemented server-side architecture on projects for Wasche & CIBN.

Education _____

Obafemi Awolowo University

Ile-ife, Nigeria

B.Sc. in Psychology (in view)

Mar. 2013 - present

Our Lady and St. Francis' Catholic College

Osogbo, Nigeria Sep. 2009 - Jul. 2012

WEST AFRICAN SENIOR SCHOOL CERTIFICATE

- Served as a member of the Student Representative Council.
- Was awarded a medal for exceptional performance in the American Mathematical Competition.

Interests

- · Reading.
- Writing Poetry and Software.
- · Learning about new technology, art and history.

References

Available on request.